Mss.Rec.107 Mss.Rec.107
American Philosophical Society
Indian Performances in Oklahoma
1973-1974
Mss.Rec.107
American Philosophical Society
36.0 Tape(s)
Recordings of powwows, benefit dances, wedding dances, dance competitions, and other permonances at various grounds in Oklahoma and Missouri from 1973-1974 by Sue Roark-Calnek. Includes round dances, stomp dances, war dances, gourd dances, snake dances, buffalo dances, hand games, and others. Dancers, singers, and staff are Arapaho, Caddo, Cayuga, Cherokee, Cheyenne, Delaware, Fox, Hopi, Kiowa, Osage, Ottawa, Oto, Pawnee, Ponca, Quapaw, Seneca, Shawnee, and Yuchi. Includes Delaware and Quapaw Pow-Wow, Osage Inloska Society, Arapaho Starhawk Society, Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow, and White Oak Shawnee Night Stomp Dance, Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow, and Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn Ceremonial and Stomp Dance.
36 sound cassettes (33 hr., 53 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo
Roark-Calnek, Sue N.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Sue Roark-Calnek in 1977. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
A detailed table of contents, including locations, dates, and names of all performance participants, is available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Dance--Competitions; Indians of North America--Oklahoma--Music; Iroquois dance; Iroquois Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma; Round dancing; Sound recordings; Stomp dance
- Audio recordings
  - Arapaho Benefit Dance (Tape 1) [Side A], 1973-12-01; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:15; Haumphy, Bruce; Lump Mouth, Keith; Night Walker, Roy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Alonzo; Tall Bull, Clarence; White Thumb, Jill; Wilson, Betty
    Scope and Contents note
    Host: Bruce Haumphy (Kiowa), Head Singer. Other singers: Kiowas, Arapahos. Starhawk (Gourd Dance) Society, Head Man Dancers. Betty Wilson (Arapaho) Head Lady Dancer. Keith Lump Mouth (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer. Jill White Thumb (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer. Clarence Tall Bull (Cheyenne) M.C.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--Music; Canton (Okla.); Kiowa dance; Powwows--Oklahoma; Round dancing
  - Arapaho Benefit Dance (Tape 1) [Side B], 1973-12-01; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:34; Haumphy, Bruce; Lump Mouth, Keith; Night Walker, Roy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Alonzo; Tall Bull, Clarence; White Thumb, Jill; Wilson, Betty
    Host: Bruce Haumphy (Kiowa), Head Singer. Other singers: Kiowas, Arapahos. Starhawk (Gourd Dance) Society, Head Man Dancers. Betty Wilson (Arapaho), Head Lady Dancer. Keith Lump Mouth (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer. Jill White Thumb (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer. Clarence Tall Bull (Cheyenne) M.C.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--Music; Canton (Okla.); Kiowa dance; Kiowa Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma
  - Arapaho Benefit Dance (Tape 2) [Side A], 1973-12-01; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:04; Haumphy, Bruce; Lump Mouth, Keith; Night Walker, Roy; Red Bird, Allen; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Alonzo; Tall Bull, Clarence; White Thumb, Jill; Wilson, Betty
  - Arapaho Benefit Dance (Tape 2) [Side B], 1973-12-01; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:28; Haumphy, Bruce; Lump Mouth, Keith; Night Walker, Roy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Alonzo; Tall Bull, Clarence; White Thumb, Jill; Wilson, Betty
    Host: Bruce Haumphy (Kiowa), Head Singer. Other singers: Kiowas, Arapahos; Starhawk (Gourd Dance) Society, Head Man Dancers. Betty Wilson (Arapaho), Head Lady Dancer. Keith Lump Mouth (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer. Jill White Thumb (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer. Clarence Tall Bull (Cheyenne) M.C.
  - Wedding Dance [Side A], 1973-12-08; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:29; Pratt, Adam; Red Bird, Jeanette; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Hosts: Mr. and Ms. Eugene Brown (Ponca) in honor of their daughter's marriage. Head Staff: Adam Pratt (Pawnee), Head Singer; Inter-Tribal Gourd (Dance) Clan of Shawnee, Head Man Dancers; Jeanette Red Bird (Arapaho) Head Lady Dancer.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--Music; Pawnee dance; Pawnee Indians--Music; Ponca City (Okla.); Shawnee Indians--Music
  - Wedding Dance [Side B], 1973-12-08; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:29; Pratt, Adam; Red Bird, Jeanette; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [1 of 2] [Side A], 1974-05-31; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:29; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Recorded at Delaware Pow-Wow Ground. Hosts: Delaware Pow-Wow Committee (Numerous Falleaf, Chairman). Head Staff: Troy Little Axe (Shawnee), Head Singer; other Singers are Shawnees, Delawares, Sac and Fox; Sonny Glass (Cherokee/Seneca-Cayuga/Quapaw), Head Man Dancer; Charla Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), Head Lady Dancer; Dee Ann Ketchum (Delaware), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
    Cherokee dance; Copan (Okla.); Delaware dance; Fox dance; Shawnee dance; Shawnee Indians--Music
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [1 of 2] [Side B], 1974-05-31; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:30; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Afternoon War Dance [Side A], 1974-06-01; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:55; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; White, Chris
    Recorded at Delaware Pow-Wow Ground. Hosts: Delaware Pow-Wow Committee (Numerous Falleaf, Chairman). Head Staff: Troy Little Axe (Shawnee), Head Singer; Other Singers are Shawnees, Delawares, Sac and Fox; Sonny Glass (Cherokee/Seneca-Cayuga/Quapaw), Head Man Dancer; Charla Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), Head Lady Dancer; Dee Ann Ketchum (Delaware), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Afternoon War Dance [Side B], 1974-06-01; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:44; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [2 of 2] [Side A], 1974-05-31; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:47; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Recorded at Delaware Pow-Wow Ground. Hosts: Delaware Pow-Wow Committee (Numerous Falleaf, Chairman). Head Staff: Troy Little Axe (Shawnee), Head Singer (Other Singers are Shawnees, Delawares, Sac and Fox); Sonny Glass (Cherokee/Seneca-Cayuga/Quapaw), Head Man Dancer; Charla Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), Head Lady Dancer; Dee Ann Ketchum (Delaware), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [2 of 2] [Side B], 1974-05-31; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:44; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest (Tape 1) [Side A], 1974-05-31; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:46; Blanchard, Rocky; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Ellis, Bert; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Kinder, Steve; Little Axe, Troy; LongHorn, Bruce; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest (Tape 1) [Side B], 1974-05-31; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:47; Bender, Judy; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Dick, Beverly; Dick, Bill; Ellis, Henrietta; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Gokey, Johnnie Mae; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Larney, Geneva; Larney, Lee; Little Axe, Troy; Long Horn, Wayne; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Runnels, Jean
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest (Tape 2) [Side A], 1974-05-31; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:42; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Dick, Beverly; Dick, Bill; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Kinder, Steve; Larney, Geneva; Larney, Lee; Little Axe, Troy; LongHorn, Bruce; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Delaware Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest (Tape 2) [Side B], 1974-05-31; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:19; Dawes, Charla; Dawes, Charles; Falleaf, Numerous; Glass, Sonny; Ketchum, Dee Ann; Larney, Geneva; Little Axe, Troy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Osage Inlonska Society ("Drum District") War Dance at Pawhuska: Afternoon and Evening Performances (Tape 1) [Side A], 1974-06-13; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:56; Lookout, Morris; Mashunkashey, John Henry; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Tindall, Raymond
    Recorded at Inlonska Dance Arbor, 'Indian Village,' Pawhuska, June 13, 1974. Afternoon performance. Hosts: Pawhuska Drum District (Ed Red Eagle, Head Committeeman and speaker, John Henry Mashunkashey, Drumkeeper). Singers: Morris Lookout (Osage) and Ponca Singers from the Heooska Society. Dancers: Pawhuska Inlonska members, visitors from the Osage Grayhorse and Hominy Drum Districts, the Ponca heooska and Otoe Elunska. In society performances, each war dance song is followed by a 'tail' restating the theme, during which only appointed 'Tail Dancers' may dance.
    Osage dance; Osage Indians--Music; Oto dance; Pawhuska (Okla.); Ponca dance; Ponca Indians--Music
  - Osage Inlonska Society ("Drum District") War Dance at Pawhuska: Afternoon and Evening Performances (Tape 1) [Side B], 1974-06-13; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:25; Lookout, Morris; Mashunkashey, John Henry; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Tindall, Raymond
    Recorded at Inlonska Dance Arbor, 'Indian Village,' Pawhuska, June 13, 1974. Evening performance. Hosts: Pawhuska Drum District (Ed Red Eagle; Head Committeeman and speaker, John Henry Mashunkashey, Drumkeeper). Singers: Morris Lookout (Osage) and Ponca Singers from the Heooska Society. Dancers: Pawhuska Inlonska members, visitors from the Osage Grayhorse and Hominy Drum Districts, the Ponca heooska and Otoe Elunska. In society performances, each war dance song is followed by a 'tail' restating the theme, during which only appointed 'Tail Dancers' may dance.
  - Osage Inlonska Society ("Drum District") War Dance at Pawhuska: Evening performance (Tape 2) [Side A], 1974-06-13; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:44; Lookout, Morris; Mashunkashey, John Henry; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Tindall, Raymond
    Recorded at Inlonska Dance Arbor, 'Indian Village,' Pawhuska, June 13, 1974. Hosts: Pawhuska Drum District (Ed Red Eagle; Head Committeeman and speaker; John Henry Mashunkashey, Drumkeeper). Singers: Morris Lookout (Osage) and Ponca Singers from the Heooska Society. Dancers: Pawhuska Inlonska members, visitors from the Osage Grayhorse and Hominy Drum Districts, the Ponca heooska and Otoe Elunska. In society performances, each war dance song is followed by a 'tail' restating the theme, during which only appointed 'Tail Dancers' may dance.
  - Osage Inlonska Society ("Drum District") War Dance at Pawhuska: Evening performance (Tape 2) [Side B], 1974-06-13; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Lookout, Morris; Mashunkashey, John Henry; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Tindall, Raymond
  - Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow Evening War Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-06-15; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:52; Bear, Sandy; Coffey, Wallace; Dawes, Kevin; Mone, Sidney, Jr.; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Talleywema, Carl; White, Chris; Whittington, Ed
    Hosts: Bushwhacker Pow-Wow Committee (White Hobbyists) (Ed Whittington, Chairman). Head Staff: Carl Talleywema (Hopi), Head Singer; A Northern-style drum--the 'Brave Scouts' led by Sidney Mone, Jr. (Pawnee/Otoe) alternates in this performance; Kevin Dawes (Ottowa/Sioux), Head Man Dancer; Sandy Bear (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; Wallace Coffey (Comanche) and Chris White (Delaware/Shawnee), MCs.
    Dance--Competitions; Hopi Indians--Music; Nevada (Mo.); Oto Indians--Music; Ottawa Indians--Music; Pawnee Indians--Music
  - Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow Evening War Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-06-15; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:13; Bear, Sandy; Coffey, Wallace; Dawes, Kevin; Mone, Sidney, Jr.; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Talleywema, Carl; White, Chris; Whittington, Ed
  - Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow Evening War Dance (tape 2) [Side A], 1974-06-15; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:49; Bear, Sandy; Coffey, Wallace; Dawes, Kevin; Mone, Sidney, Jr.; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Talleywema, Carl; White, Chris; Whittington, Ed
  - Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow Evening War Dance (tape 2) [Side B], 1974-06-15; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:01; Bear, Sandy; Coffey, Wallace; Dawes, Kevin; Mone, Sidney, Jr.; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Talleywema, Carl; White, Chris; Whittington, Ed
    Hosts: Bushwhacker Pow-Wow Committee (White Hobbyists) (Ed Whittington, Chairman). Head Staff: Carl Talleywema (Hopi), Head Singer; A Northern-style drum--the 'Brave Scouts' led by Sidney Mone, Jr. (Pawnee/Otoe) alternates in this performance; Kevin Dawes (Ottowa/Sioux), Head Man Dancer; Sandy Bear (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; Wallace Coffey (Comanche), and Chris White (Delaware/Shawnee) MCs.
  - Nevada (Mo.) Bushwhacker Days Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest, 1974-06-15; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:43; Blalock, Billy Charles; Blalock, Jim; Blalock, Joyce; Dawes, Kevin; Dick, Beverly; Kinder, Steve; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Runnels, Jean; Valier, Mary Louise; White, Chris; Whittington, Ed
    Recorded at Nevada Fair Ground, June 15, 1974). Hosts: Bushwhacker Pow-Wow Committee (White Hobbyists) (Ed Whittington, Chairman). Head Staff: Leaders and Shell-shakers as identified; Chris White (Delaware/Shawnee), M.C.
    Comanche dance; Delaware dance; Nevada (Mo.); Ottawa dance; Powwows--Oklahoma; Shawnee dance
  - White Oak Shawnee Night Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-06-22; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:59; Bob, Frank; Brown, Jess; Carpenter, Emmeline; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Squirrel, James
    Recorded at White Oak Ceremonial Ground, near White Oak, Oklahoma, June 22, 1974. Hosts: White Oak Shawnee Ceremonial Organization; Frank Bob; Chief Emmeline Carpenter, Head 'Old Lady'. Singers: Bill Shawnee (Shawnee/Delaware); James Squirrel (Shawnee); Jess Brown (Shawnee). Dancers: Shawnees from host ground, Delawares, Quapaws and Otoes from the 'Eight Tribes' of Ottawa County. Instruments: water drum, gourd rattles, (Lead Dance) leg shackles.
    Oto dance; Powwows--Oklahoma; Quapaw dance; Shawnee dance; White Oak (Okla.)
  - White Oak Shawnee Night Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-06-22; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:48; Bob, Frank; Brown, Jess; Carpenter, Emmeline; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Squirrel, James
  - White Oak Shawnee Night Stomp Dance (tape 2), 1974-06-22; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:45; Bob, Frank; Brown, Jess; Carpenter, Emmeline; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Squirrel, James
  - Albert Watters (Ponca) Birthday Dance: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side A], 1974-06-29; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:36; Buffalo Head, Harry; Conklin, Abe; Jones, Sharon; Mokai, Len; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Watters, Albert
    Recorded at Gives Water Hall Dance Arbor, near White Eagle, Oklahoma, on June 29, 1974. Hosts: Albert Watters Family, in honor of the birthday of the dean of Ponca War Dance Singers. Singers: Harry Buffalo Head (Ponca), Head Singer, others singers are Poncas. Dancers: Ponca City Inter-tribal Gourd Dance Society.
    Birthday parties; Kay County (Okla.); Ponca dance; Ponca Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma
  - Albert Watters (Ponca) Birthday Dance: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side B], 1974-06-29; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:10; Buffalo Head, Harry; Conklin, Abe; Jones, Sharon; Mokai, Len; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Watters, Albert
  - Albert Watters (Ponca) Birthday Dance: Evening Gourd Dance and War Dance [Side A], 1974-06-29; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:57; Buffalo Head, Harry; Conklin, Abe; Jones, Sharon; Mokai, Len; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Watters, Albert
    Recorded at Gives Water Hall Dance Arbor, near White Eagle, Oklahoma, on June 29, 1974. Hosts: Albert Watters Family, in honor of the birthday of the dean of Ponca War Dance Singers. Head Staff: Harry Buffalo Head (Ponca) Head Singer. Gourd Dancers: Ponca City Inter-Tribal Gourd Dance Society; Abe Conklin (Ponca), Head Man Dancer; Sharon Jones (Ponca), Head Lady Dancer; Len Mokai (Comanche), M.C.
  - Albert Watters (Ponca) Birthday Dance: Evening Gourd Dance and War Dance [Side B], 1974-06-29; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:49; Buffalo Head, Harry; Conklin, Abe; Jones, Sharon; Mokai, Len; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Watters, Albert
  - Otoe Elunska Benefit Hand Game [Side A], 1974-06-30; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:23; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Hosts: Otoe Elunska Society, to raise funds for purchase of a public address system for society dances. Each game is followed by a victory Round Dance for the winning side, after which contributions are made to the hosts.
    Oto dance; Powwows--Oklahoma; Red Rock (Okla.); Round dancing
  - Otoe Elunska Benefit Hand Game [Side B], 1974-06-30; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:37; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-07-04; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:51; Dawes, Charles; Gilmore, Harry; Kowell, JoKay; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; Skye, Lenny; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 4, 1974). Hosts: Quapaw Pow-Wow Committee (Harry Gilmore, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; (Other singers are Ponca); Lenny Skye (Quapaw/Peoria), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; JoKay Dowell (Quapaw), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
    Dance--Competitions; Ponca Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma; Quapaw (Okla.); Quapaw dance
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-07-04; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:37; Dawes, Charles; Gilmore, Harry; Kowell, JoKay; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; Skye, Lenny; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at: Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 4, 1974. Hosts: Quapaw Pow-Wow Committee (Harry Gilmore, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; other singers are Ponca; Lenny Skye (Quapaw/Peoria), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; JoKay Dowell (Quapaw), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance (tape 2), 1974-07-04; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:12; Dawes, Charles; Gilmore, Harry; Kowell, JoKay; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; Skye, Lenny; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 4, 1974. Hosts: Quapaw Pow-Wow Committee (Harry Gilmore, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; other singers are Ponca; Lenny Skye (Quapaw/Peoria), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; JoKay Dowell (Quapaw), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [Side A], 1974-07-05; 21-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:40; Dawes, Charles; Gilmore, Harry; Kowell, JoKay; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; Skye, Lenny; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at: Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 5, 1974. Hosts: Quapaw Pow-Wow Committee (Harry Gilmore, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; other singers are Ponca; Lenny Skye (Quapaw/Peoria), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; JoKay Dowell (Quapaw), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [Side B], 1974-07-05; 21-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:14; Dawes, Charles; Gilmore, Harry; Kowell, JoKay; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; Skye, Lenny; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at: Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 5, 1974). Hosts: Quapaw Pow-Wow Committee (Harry Gilmore, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; other singers are Ponca; Lenny Skye (Quapaw/Peoria), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; JoKay Dowell (Quapaw), Princess; Charles Dawes (Ottawa/Sioux), M.C.
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest [Side A], 1974-07-05; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:02; Adkins, Vernon; Kinder, Kenny; Kinder, Steve; Longhorn, Wayne; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Recorded at Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 5, 1974, by Kenny Kinder (Peoria). Leaders and shell-shakers as identified. Almost all participants are Quapaws and others of the 'Eight Tribes' of Ottawa County, and Shawnees and the Whiteoak and Little Axe Grounds.
    Dance--Competitions; Powwows--Oklahoma; Quapaw (Okla.); Quapaw dance; Shawnee dance; Shawnee Indians--Music
  - Quapaw Pow-Wow: Stomp Dance Contest [Side B], 1974-07-05; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:22; Blalock, Billy Charles; Dick, Beverly; Dick, Bill; Gibson, Elsie; Kinder, Kenny; LongHorn, Bruce; McClellan, Patsy; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Runnels, Jean; Vailer, George
    Recorded at: Beaver Springs ('Devil's Promenade') ground, near Quapaw, Oklahoma, July 5, 1974, by Kenny Kinder (Peoria). Leaders and shell-shakers as identified. Almost all participants are Quapaws and others of the 'Eight Tribes' of Ottawa County, and Shawnees and the Whiteoak and Little Axe Grounds.
  - Arapaho Starhawk (Gourd Dance) Society Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side A], 1974-08-03; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:48; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam
    Recorded at Barefoot Park, near Canton, Oklahoma, August 3, 1974. Hosts: Starhawk Society (Stanley Sleeper, Chairman). Head Staff: Harrison Hunter (Sac and Fox), Head Singer; Other singers are Cheyenne, Caddo, Kiowa; Danny Lee Wilson (Delaware/Arapaho), Head Man Dancer; Jannelle Orange (Arapaho), Head Lady Dancer; Scotty Sankey (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer; Marcella Sutton (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer; Howard Good Bear and Sam Young Bear (Cheyenne/Arapaho), MCs.
    Caddo Indians--Music; Canton (Okla.); Cheyenne Indians--Music; Fox dance; Kiowa Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma
  - Arapaho Starhawk (Gourd Dance) Society Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side B], 1974-08-03; 23-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:00; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam
  - Arapaho Starhawk Society Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd Dance and War Dance [Side A], 1974-08-03; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:55; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam
  - Arapaho Starhawk Society Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd Dance and War Dance [Side B], 1974-08-03; 24-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:45; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam
    Recorded at Barefoot Park, near Canton, Oklahoma, August 3, 1974. Hosts: Starhawk Society (Stanley Sleeper, Chairman). Head Staff: Harrison Hunter (Sac and Fox), Head Singer. Other singers are Cheyenne, Caddo, Kiowa. Danny Lee Wilson (Delaware/Arapaho), Head Man Dancer. Jannelle Orange (Arapaho), Head Lady Dancer. Scotty Sankey (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer. Marcella Sutton (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer. Howard Good Bear and Sam Young Bear (Cheyenne/Arapaho), MCs.
  - Arapaho Starhawk Society Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance, 1974-08-04; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:13; Fan Man, David; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam